trinet.com 2017-01-28

# Terms of Use and Privacy Policy | TriNet

## Privacy Policy

Effective Date: 09/28/2016

## Introduction - www.trinet.com

This privacy policy applies to the website [www.trinet.com](http://www.trinet.com/) and to TriNet services websites at: [www.trinetambrose.com](http://www.trinetambrose.com/), [www.trinetpassport.com](http://www.trinetpassport.com/), [www.trinetsoi.com](http://www.trinetsoi.com/), [www.trinetlifesciences.com](http://www.trinetlifesciences.com/), and [www.trinetaccord.com](http://www.trinetaccord.com/).These websites are owned and operated by TriNet Group, Inc. and its subsidiaries (“TriNet”). This privacy policy describes how TriNet collects and uses the personal information you provide on our websites. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

TriNet delivers HR outsourcing services that allow companies to do what they do best. Thousands of employers have turned to TriNet for human resources, benefits, payroll, workers' compensation and strategic human capital services. As their trusted HR advisor, TriNet helps these employers contain HR costs, minimize employer-related risk and relieve the administrative burden of HR. In order for TriNet to provide this vast array of services to its customers and their worksite employees, TriNet must collect certain personal information regarding the employees of its customers.

Protecting the privacy of users of TriNet products and services is important to TriNet. TriNet makes use of any personal information you provide to TriNet only for the purposes outlined in this policy. To the extent TriNet's International Privacy Policy ("International Policy") is also applicable to your personal information and if there is any conflict between the terms of this policy and the International Policy, the terms of the International Policy will govern.

This policy does not apply to any information that you may provide directly to third parties including via third-party sites linked to the TriNet.com website or TriNet’s service websites. While TriNet actively seeks to ensure that its suppliers and service providers maintain high standards regarding the protection of personal information collected on their websites, TriNet is not responsible for the privacy practices employed by such sites.

## EU-U.S. Privacy Shield

TriNet Group, Inc. (and its subsidiary companies such as TriNet HR Corporation, Strategic Outsourcing, Inc., Ambrose Employer Group, LLC and Accord Human Resources, Inc.) participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. TriNet is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the [U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List.](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list)

TriNet is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. TriNet complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, TriNet is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, TriNet may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the [Privacy Shield website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint), you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

## U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor Framework

TriNet complies with the U.S. – Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from Switzerland. TriNet has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view TriNet certification, please visit [http://www.export.gov/safeharbor.](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor)

## Information We Collect

The TriNet.com website collects identifying information such as, your name, company name, company address and other contact information. We, TriNet, will never sell, rent, lend or trade this information in our possession to any other company for the purpose of contacting you regarding commercial services. If you are a TriNet customer or worksite employee of a customer, we collect the information necessary to provide our services, collecting it either from you directly or from your worksite employer. This collection is limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the customer has engaged TriNet. By voluntarily providing information or by accessing our websites, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your personally identifiable information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and, if applicable, the International Policy.

When you download and/or use our services, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier (or "UDID"). We do not ask for, access or track any location-based information from your mobile device at any time while downloading or using our mobile apps or services.

## Usage Tracking and Cookies

Technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by TriNet and our affiliates, analytics service providers, and third party providers of HR services we have engaged. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an aggregated basis and, in the case of registered users, on an individual basis, as well.

For example we track user traffic patterns throughout all of our sites, but this tracking is never associated with non-registered individual users. We compile aggregate data mainly by tallying page views throughout our sites. This information may include the URL that you just came from (whether this URL is on our site or not), which URL you go to next (whether this URL is on our site or not), and what browser and computing platform you are using.

In addition, we use cookies on certain pages of our sites. We may also offer certain features that are only available through the use of a cookie. Cookies enable you to enter your password less frequently during a session. Cookies can also help us provide you information that is targeted to your interests. Cookies are stored on your hard drive, not on our sites. Most cookies are "session cookies," meaning they are automatically deleted at the end of a session. We also use persistent cookies. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time and remembers your preferences. You are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits, although in that case you may not be able to use certain features on our sites, and you may be required to reenter your password more frequently during a session. Our affiliates, tracking utility company, and service providers use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site.

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. To manage Flash cookies please click [here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information.

If you send us proposals or personal correspondence, such as emails or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on our sites, we may collect and store such information in a file specific to you. If you submit questions via our sites, we may post your questions on the sites, and reprint them in various articles and customer communications. We will never include the name, contact or other identifiable information of people who submit questions, regardless of which channel we use to distribute content.

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other websites. Our third party partner may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you with advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).) Please note that you will continue to receive generic ads.

## Use of Information

We use personally identifiable information about you to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, statistically analyze site usage, improve our content product offerings, customize our sites' content, layout and services, and provide our services (if applicable).

We may use the email address, mailing address, and phone number we collect from you to respond to your inquiries and, to the extent permitted by applicable law, to contact you regarding administrative notices, new product offerings and communications relevant to your use of our sites. In some cases, we may use your personally identifiable information to inform you of new services, promotions and other matters targeted to your interests. You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or by contacting the appropriate customer support office.

We use information in the file we maintain specific to you, and other information we obtain from your current and past activities on our sites, to resolve disputes and troubleshoot problems. At times, we may look across multiple users to identify problems or resolve disputes and we may evaluate information about you to look for users using multiple User IDs or aliases.

## Children's Privacy

TriNet’s websites are intended for adults. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we obtain knowledge that we have personally identifiable information about a child under 13 in retrievable form in our files, we will delete that information from our existing files. However, we will retain information from adult registered users about their dependents for purposes of administering benefits for their dependents, including dependents under the age of 13.

## Customers and Worksite Employees of TriNet

If you are a customer (also referred to as a worksite employer) or worksite employee serviced by TriNet, you are a registered user and we may collect and maintain personally identifiable information including, but not limited to, name, address, phone number, social security number, taxpayer identification number, age, marital status, occupation, salary, benefits, dependent information, etc. through TriNet service websites or other means disclosed to you. This information will be used to provide our professional employer and other HR-related services, which may include sharing such information with your worksite employer to the extent permitted by applicable law.

Once you receive a username and password, you can review and change the information you submitted during registration. If your registration information changes, you must promptly update, change or delete your registration information by logging into your information page or by contacting the appropriate customer support office. We will respond to your inquiries about your personal information within 30 days. We may retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. Further, such prior information is never completely removed from our databases due to technical constraints and the fact that we back up our systems. Therefore, you should not expect that all of your personally identifiable information will be completely removed from our databases in response to your requests.

## Disclosure of Information

Unfortunately, due to the existing regulatory environment, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personally identifiable information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this policy. By way of example (without limiting the foregoing): we may be forced to disclose information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, such as to comply with a subpoena or similar legal process; we may use information when we believe in good faith that it is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others; and we may respond to any other third party requests with your prior consent to do so.

Third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. Therefore, although we employ industry-standard practices to protect your privacy, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personally identifiable information or private communications will always remain private.

As a general proposition, we do not sell, rent, lend or trade any personally identifiable information about you to any third party. The following paragraphs describe some of the ways that personally identifiable information about you may be disclosed to third parties..

## Legal Requests

We cooperate with law enforcement and other third parties to enforce laws, intellectual property rights and other rights. Therefore, local, state, federal, territorial, provincial and international law enforcement can request and may receive your personally identifiable information. By your use of the TriNet.com website, TriNet’s service websites, or TriNet's services (as applicable), you hereby accept these terms and you authorize us to disclose any information about you to law enforcement or other government officials as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate, in connection with an investigation of fraud, intellectual property infringements or other activity that is illegal or may expose us to legal liability.

## Business Transactions

We reserve the right to transfer personally identifiable information as part of a sale or transfer of all or a relevant portion of our business or assets. Any such sale would be subject to appropriate privacy protections for you. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personally identifiable information.

## Suppliers and Other Service Providers

We may use third-party suppliers and service providers to facilitate provision of our professional employer and HR-related services. For example, we may outsource the operations of one or more aspects of our sites to a supplier or service provider who performs services according to our requirements. In all cases, we restrict how these suppliers and other service providers may access, use and disclose information received from our websites. We do not permit these suppliers and other service providers to access information about you, other than that information necessary for them to complete the services for which they are contracted. Under no circumstances do we allow them to disclose, sell, rent, lend, trade or in any other way transmit data about you to third parties, and we use contractual means to require them to provide appropriate protection for your personally identifiable information and to use it only for the services for which they are contracted.

## Retention of Information

We retain personally identifiable information that we collect only so long as reasonably necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected and to meet legal requirements. We have a Business Record Retention Policy and an E-mail Retention Policy which provide for the destruction of personally identifiable information after it is no longer needed for the purposes for which it was collected and legal requirements have been met.

## Security

We use industry standard methods, such as firewalls and Secure Socket Layers (SSL), to safeguard the confidentiality of personally identifiable information about you. For registered users, personally identifiable information will include name, address, contact information, social security number, date of birth and payroll and benefits information related to the services we provide to registered users. Using SSL means that data such as names and passwords cannot be easily deciphered by outside users.

## Referrals

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our website, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. You must have the consent of your friend to provide us with this information. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the website. This email will identify that you asked for it to be sent. TriNet may store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact the appropriate customer support office to request that we remove this information from our database.

## Social Media Widgets

Our website includes social media features, such as the Facebook button, and widgets, such as the ShareThis button, or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## Access

We will allow you access to your Personal Information and allow you to correct, amend or delete inaccurate information, except to the extent permitted by applicable law where the burden or expense of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks to your privacy in the case in question or where the rights of persons other than you would be violated. If access to Personal Information is denied, we will provide you with the reason for such denial. You may request the correction, amendment or deletion of your innacurate personal information by contacting us at myhr@trinet.com. We will respond to these requests within a reasonable timeframe.

## Changes in this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to change this policy at any time without prior notice to users of this site. This Privacy Policy was last updated on September 28, 2016. Please check here regularly to learn of any changes to this policy. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email or by means of a notice on this site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

## Copyright Notification

TriNet.com and TriNet’s other service websites are the property of TriNet. ©2016, All rights reserved. 

## Trademark Information

The TriNet logo and design and Ambitions Realized® are registered trademarks of TriNet. All other trademarks, trade names, service marks and logos appearing on the TriNet website and TriNet’s service websites belong to their respective companies.

## Website Administrator

Send comments to TriNet.com [Website Support](mailto:siteforms@trinet.com).

## Contact Information

TriNet  
1100 San Leandro Boulevard  
Suite 400  
San Leandro, CA 94577, USA  
Attention: Chief Legal Officer  
Email the appropriate customer support office or [legal@trinet.com](mailto:legal@trinet.com)

## International Privacy Policy - www.trinet.com

**This Privacy Policy applies only to Personal Information transferred to TriNet Group Inc., and its subsidiaries ("TriNet") from locations in the European Union ("EU"), Switzerland, Canada and other locations outside of the United States. In addition, all other personal information transferred to TriNet is subject to TriNet's "Privacy Policy and Terms of Use" posted on**[ **www.trinet.com**](http://www.trinet.com/) **,**[ **www.trinetambrose.com**](http://www.trinetambrose.com/) **,**[ **www.trinetpassport.com**](http://www.trinetpassport.com/) **,**[ **www.trinetsoi.com**](http://www.trinetsoi.com/) **,**[ **www.trinetlifesciences.com**](http://www.trinetlifesciences.com/) **and**[ **www.trinetaccord.com**](http://www.trinetaccord.com/) **. To the extent TriNet’s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy is also applicable to your personal information and there is any conflict between the terms of this International Privacy Policy and TriNet’s Terms of Use and Privacy Policy, the terms of this International Policy will govern.**

## Introduction

TriNet delivers HR outsourcing services that allow companies to do what they do best. Thousands of employers have turned to TriNet for human resources, benefits, payroll, workers' compensation and strategic human capital services. As their trusted HR advisor, TriNet helps these employers contain HR costs, minimize employer-related risk and relieve the administrative burden of HR. TriNet's suite of HR outsourcing services includes coordination of services to its customers’ locations and worksite employees outside of the United States. In order for TriNet to provide this vast array of services, TriNet must collect certain personal information regarding the worksite employees of its customers.

Protecting customer and employee privacy is important to TriNet. TriNet adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles concerning the transfer of personal data from locations in the European Union (EU) and Switzerland to the United States and adheres to Canada’s Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act ("PIPEDA") and the applicable provincial privacy legislation.

This Privacy Policy applies to all Personal Information received by TriNet from outside of the United States whether in electronic, paper or verbal format. All such information is transmitted to the United States and is maintained in San Leandro, California; Reno, Nevada; Bradenton, Florida; Oklahoma City, Oklahoma; Fort Mill, South Carolina; and New York City, New York, which may have privacy and data protection laws that differ from those in the country in which an employee resides. As a result, Personal Information may be subject to access requests from U.S. government agencies, courts and law enforcement officials in accordance with U.S. laws.

## Definition of Personal Information

"Personal Information" or "Information" means information that 1) is transferred from outside of the United States to TriNet; 2) is recorded in any form; 3) is about or pertains to a specific individual; and 4) can be linked to that individual. Accordingly, this policy applies to you if information linked to you is transferred to TriNet in any recorded form from outside the United States.

## Privacy Shield Principles

TriNet Group, Inc. (and its subsidiary companies such as TriNet HR Corporation, Strategic Outsourcing, Inc., Ambrose Employer Group, LLC and Accord Human Resources, Inc.) participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. TriNet is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the [U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

TriNet is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. TriNet complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, TriNet is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, TriNet may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) [here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the [Privacy Shield website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint), you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

**Notice:** We, TriNet, will inform you of the purpose for which we collect and use the Personal Information and the types of non-agent third parties to which we disclose or may disclose that Personal Information. We will provide you with the choice and means to limit our use and disclosure of your Personal Information for a purpose other than that for which it was originally collected.

Personal Information includes, but is not limited to: name, employer, title, position held, length of employment, documents that verify employment, work address, work phone number, home address, home phone number, country of domicile, copy of government identity card, copy of passport, date of birth, gender, marital status, family status, compensation, salary information, tax information, names and birthdates of dependents and bank information. This Personal Information is transmitted to payroll and benefit providers and other vendors that participate in providing customers’ payroll, benefits and other related services.

**Choice:** We will offer you the opportunity to choose (opt out) whether your Personal Information is 1) to be disclosed to a third party (other than a vendor or service provider we have contracted with in connection with providing payroll, benefits and other related services) or 2) to be used for a purpose other than the purpose for which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized by you. We will obtain express consent when required by applicable law.

**Onward Transfers:** Prior to disclosing Personal Information to a third party (other than the service providers referred to above), we will notify you of such disclosure and allow you a choice (opt out) regarding such disclosure. We will ensure that any third party to which Personal Information may be disclosed subscribes to the Principles or is subject to law providing the same level of privacy protection as is required by the Principles or agrees in writing to provide an adequate level of privacy protection.

**Data Security:** We will take reasonable steps, proportionate to the sensitivity of the Personal Information, to protect Personal Information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. We have put in place appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure Personal Information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration or destruction. However, we cannot guarantee the security of Information on, or transmitted via, the Internet.

**Data Integrity:** We will only process and use Personal Information in a way that is compatible with and relevant for the purposes for which it was collected or authorized by you, including the purposes to provide payroll, benefits and related services. To the extent necessary for those purposes, we will take reasonable precautions to ensure that Personal Information is as accurate, complete, current and reliable as necessary for its intended use. Personal Information may only be accessed by persons within our organization or third-party suppliers and service providers who require such access to provide you with the services indicated above.

**Access:** We will allow you access to your Personal Information and allow you to correct, amend or delete inaccurate information, except, to the extent permitted by applicable law, where the burden or expense of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks to your privacy in the case in question or where the rights of persons other than you would be violated. If access to Personal Information is denied, we will provide you with the reason for such denial. You may request the correction, amendment or deletion of your innacurate personal information by contacting us at myhr@trinet.com. We will respond to these requests within a reasonable timeframe.

**Enforcement:** We use a self-assessment approach to assure compliance with this Privacy Policy and periodically verify that the policy is accurate, comprehensive for the information intended to be covered, prominently displayed, completely implemented and accessible, and in conformity with the Principles. We encourage interested persons to raise any concerns using the contact information provided and we will investigate and attempt to resolve any complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of Personal Information in accordance with the Principles and this Privacy Policy.

## Amendments

This Privacy Policy was last updated on September 28, 2016, and may be amended from time to time by the posting of a revised policy on this website. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email or by means of a notice on this site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

## Privacy Complaints by Residents Outside of the United States

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, we commit to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your Personal Information. If you have any inquiries or complaints regarding this Privacy Policy, you should first contact us at:

TriNet  
1100 San Leandro Boulevard  
Suite 400  
San Leandro, CA 94577, USA  
Attention: Chief Legal Officer  
Email the appropriate [customer support office](http://trinet.com/company/contact_us/default.htm#horizontalTab2) or [legal@trinet.com](mailto:legal@trinet.com)

If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact TRUSTe [here](https://www.truste.com/consumer-resources/dispute-resolution/).

If you are a Canadian resident and are not able to resolve your concern by contacting us, you may contact your provincial Privacy Commissioner or the Privacy Commissioner of Canada [here](http://www.priv.gc.ca/cu-cn/index_e.asp).

See more [here](http://www.trinet.com/company/terms.htm#sthash.onprBGcA.dpuf).

## Terms of Use

In addition to the applicable privacy policy, the following terms of use apply to your use of [www.trinet.com](http://www.trinet.com/) and to TriNet’s service websites:[www.trinetambrose.com](http://www.trinetambrose.com/), [www.trinetpassport.com](http://www.trinetpassport.com/), [www.trinetsoi.com](http://www.trinetsoi.com/), [www.trinetlifesciences.com](http://www.trinetlifesciences.com/), and [www.trinetaccord.com](https://access.accordhr.com/login/). These websites are owned and operated by TriNet Group, Inc., and it subsidiaries (“TriNet”). The content of the websites is protected by U.S. and international copyright laws, federal and states trademark laws and other intellectual property laws and conventions. Nothing contained in these websites will be construed as granting any license or right to use the protected materials, without the express written consent of TriNet. By accessing or otherwise using the websites, you are indicating your acceptance of, and agreement to abide by, these terms of use, the applicable privacy policies and all applicable international federal, state and local laws and regulations.

## Use of Service Websites

TriNet’s service websites are licensed to you subject to the terms and conditions set forth here and in any acknowledgment for a specific service website. You agree that all information submitted by you to a TriNet service website is and will be true and correct. You agree that the service website you access constitutes confidential, proprietary, intellectual property of TriNet, that this license is revocable by TriNet at any time, and that you will not modify, reverse engineer, decompile or disassemble, or otherwise tamper with the service website or create any derivative works or otherwise incorporate the service website in other programs, without TriNet’s prior written consent. Any feedback you provide will become TriNet information and TriNet will have the royalty-free right to share the feedback and to create and use derivative works based on the feedback.

## As Is

Your licensed usage of TriNet’s service websites is on an “As Is” basis and TriNet disclaims any and all warranties, express or implied, to the full extent permitted by law. For example, TriNet does not warrant that its online services or content will be uninterrupted or error-free, available at all times, or in any and all geographic areas, or will meet any particular criteria of performance or quality. TriNet cannot be held liable for any indirect, punitive, incidental, consequential, or other special damages arising out of your use of TriNet’s service websites or online services.

## Control of Your Login Password—for Customers and Worksite Employees Only

Except as specifically permitted by this section, you may not disclose your password to access TriNet’s service websites to any third party or share it with any third party. If you lose control of your password, you may lose substantial control over personally identifiable information about you and may be subject to the consequences of actions taken on your behalf. Therefore, if your password has been compromised for any reason, you should immediately change your password and notify us that you believe your password has been compromised. You may, however, disclose your password to certain third parties with whom we have entered into specific contractual and technical arrangements designed to safeguard your password ("Authorized Password Users"), in order to enjoy the benefits of those third parties' services in relation to our services.

## Minors

TriNet websites are not intended for use by children, especially those under age 13. No one under age 13 is allowed to use the websites, provide any personal information or receive our email distributions. Minors between the ages of 13 and 17 must be properly employed as a worksite employee or have the permission of a parent or legal guardian in order to use the websites, provide any personal information or receive our email distributions.

## TriNet Benefit Plans Disclaimer

TriNet is not an insurance company and nothing contained herein constitutes an offer to sell, buy, or procure insurance. We are the single employer sponsor of all our benefit plans. We make these plans available to qualifying worksite employees with whom we have established an employment relationship and who perform services for our customers in a Professional Employer Organization ("PEO") service model. Under this model, we incur all expenses associated with our plan sponsorship and maintenance and we bill the customer for our services.

Other than compliance with TriNet’s contract terms, customers have no other financial obligation to us, our other customers, worksite employees or any of our insurance carriers for benefit plans sponsorship or provision. Our carriers have recourse against TriNet and not against our customers for premiums and expenses associated with plan sponsorship.

Any references to "your benefit programs or plans" are not legal terms or terms of art and should not be confused with legal plan sponsorship, participation or fiduciary compliance. These terms and others, such as "your employees" or "your selections, plan, or investments," are used solely as lay terms of convenience so that you understand we are referring only to the decisions made and TriNet plans available in a specific worksite or to a specific group of worksite employees.

Insurance coverage exclusions and limitations apply. In the event there is a conflict between any of the information contained in any benefits guidance materials we provide (including but not limited to information contained in any TriNet website, the Benefits Confirmation Statement, any written or electronic pamphlets, letters, emails, text messages and statements made by TriNet employees) and TriNet's Plan document, the Plan document will control. Also, if there is a conflict between an official certificate provided by our insurance carrier(s) (the "Carrier Certificate") and either TriNet's Plan document, any TriNet Summary Plan Description, statements made by a TriNet employee or any other benefits guidance materials provided by TriNet (including but not limited to those described above), the Carrier Certificate will control.

## Changes and Applicable Law

The information on TriNet’s websites may have general applicability to TriNet customers and worksite employees and is not deemed to amend, alter or supersede specific contracts or agreements. TriNet reserves the right to change the terms of use and privacy policies contained herein at any time and such charges will become effective after TriNet posts the changes on this website. Any dispute regarding the terms of use will be resolved by arbitration conducted in the city of the TriNet office closest to your most recent work location. The arbitration will be in accordance with the rules and processes of either the American Arbitration Association or Judicial Arbitration and Mediation Services, Inc., and, for state law, the law of Delaware will apply.

## Legal Disclaimer

The TriNet.com and TriNet’s service websites contain a great deal of content regarding legal and human resource matters. The content has been prepared for educational and information purposes only and does not provide legal advice or legal opinions on any specific matters. Transmission of information over the Internet is not intended to create, and receipt does not constitute, a lawyer-client relationship between TriNet, the author(s), or the publishers and you. You should not act or refrain from acting on any legal matter based on TriNet.com or TriNet’s service website content without seeking professional counsel.
